Amory Nelson Hardy Photographs MS223
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Amory Nelson Hardy Photographs
1883 -- 1885
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Hardy, Amory Nelson
MS223
0.55 Linear Feet 1 box
20 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
This collection of photographs was discovered at the Rhode Island School of Design Museum by curator Elizabeth Williams. She contacted DCA in September 2014 and offered them to us. They were accessioned in October 2014.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains print photographs of the Tufts campus taken by Boston photographer Amory N. Hardy. The photographs capture the scenery of Tufts at a time when the campus was expanding with the construction of new buildings, such as Barnum Hall, Goddard Chapel, and Goddard Gymnasium (later renamed Goddard Hall), in the 1880s. They also display contemporary events on campus, such as a baseball game and Daniel Pratt's May 1885 lecture outside Packard Hall.
Related Materials
MS054 Edward B. Rollins papers
UA136 Historical materials collection
Biographical / Historical
Amory Nelson Hardy was a Boston photographer in the late nineteenth and early twentieth century. Hardy was born in Carmel, Maine on July 16, 1834 to Benjamin Hardy and Eliza Nevine. During his career, he maintained a studio in several different locations in Boston, including Winter Street and Washington Street. On February 24, 1911 Hardy died from acute bronchitis at his home in Somerville, Massachusetts. He was seventy-six years old.
University history; Tufts University -- History
- Amory Nelson Hardy photographs, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001; 0.55 Linear Feet; 20 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains twenty print photographs of the Tufts campus taken by Boston photographer Amory N. Hardy. The photographs capture the scenery of Tufts at a time when the campus was expanding with the construction of new buildings, such as Barnum Hall, Goddard Chapel, and Goddard Gymnasium (later renamed Goddard Hall), in the 1880s. They also display contemporary events on campus, such as a baseball game and Daniel Pratt's May 1885 lecture outside Packard Hall.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged according to preservation and storage needs.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Capen House, 8 Professors Row, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Professors Row; Capen House; Houses; photographic prints
  - Tufts railroad station, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    Medford (Mass.); Railroad stations; photographic prints
  - Ballou Hall, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Ballou Hall; Buildings; photographic prints
  - Goddard Gymnasium, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Goddard Gymnasium; Goddard Hall; Buildings; Gymnasiums; photographic prints
  - East Hall, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; East Hall; Buildings; Dormitories; photographic prints
  - View of Tufts campus and construction of Barnum Hall, 1883 -- 1884; MS223.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    Buildings visible in the photograph are West Hall, Goddard Gymnasium, Barnum Hall (under construction), East Hall, and Goddard Chapel.
    Medford Campus; West Hall; Goddard Chapel; Goddard Gymnasium; Goddard Hall; East Hall; Barnum Hall; Buildings; Dormitories; Gymnasiums; Chapels; Construction; photographic prints
  - Baseball game at Tufts, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    Buildings visible are the homes of Professor Shipman, Fay, and Bray.
    Medford Campus; Fay House; Shipman House; 98 Professors Row; Baseball; Sports; Housing; photographic prints
  - Packard Hall and East Hall, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Packard Hall; East Hall; Buildings; Dormitories; photographic prints
  - View of Tufts campus, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    Buildings visible in the photograph are West Hall, East Hall, Barnum Hall, Ballou Hall, and Goddard Chapel.
    Medford Campus; West Hall; Goddard Chapel; East Hall; Barnum Hall; Ballou Hall; Buildings; Dormitories; Chapels; photographic prints
  - Interior view of Goddard Chapel, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Goddard Chapel; Chapels; photographic prints
  - Goddard Chapel, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Barnum Hall, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Barnum Hall; Buildings; photographic prints
  - Daniel Pratt delivering a lecture to a group of men, 1885-05; MS223.001.001.00013; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box 1)
    This lecture was given to Tufts students outside Packard Hall.
    Medford Campus; Packard Hall; Buildings; Dormitories; Lectures or lecturing; Students; photographic prints; Pratt, Daniel
  - Ballou Hall, view through trees, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - View of bridge and road adjacent to Tufts railroad station, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Goddard Chapel, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Young man lying on lawn overlooking Professors Row, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Professors Row; photographic prints
  - Baseball game at Tufts, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Baseball; Sports; photographic prints
  - View of trees adjacent to Goddard Chapel, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Packard Hall, 1883 -- 1885; MS223.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
    Medford Campus; Packard Hall; Buildings; photographic prints